Sorry, but I'm going out, Diao.
（信(しん)）悪いが
俺 出かけるぜ 貂(てん)
Xin
（貂）どこへ？
（信）ああ ちょっとな
Where?
Well... it'll just be for a bit.
（貂）
晩メシまでに帰ってくるのか？
Will you be back for dinner?
いや
（貂）じゃ…
Nope.
Then when?
さあ？ このまま
次の戦に行っちまうかもしんねえし
Dunno.
I might head straight to the next war after this.
I can't say for sure.
はっきり分かんねえよ
He Liao Diao
You don't know?
〝分かんねえ〞って…
行ってくる！
I'm goin'!
Xin...
信…
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
human desire was unleashed.
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years...
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦(しん)から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
G_I_A
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Now's the only time.
～♪
A New Trial
*Xin's Manager
Yuan
（渕(えん)）アア…
Mornin', Mr. Yuan!
おはよう！ 渕さん
（渕）おはようございます
Good morning.
Is there something you need, so early in the morning?
こんな早くに何か？
（信）ああ！
Yeah.
実は 連れていってもらいたい所が
あってね ちょっと
Actually, there's a place I'd like you to bring me on a little trip to.
“ちょっと”？
Little trip...?
So, Lord Xin, where is this little trip to?
（渕）
それで 信どの “ちょっと”とは？
General Wang Qi's castle.
（信）王騎(おうき)将軍の城！
お… 王騎将軍～？
General Wang Qi?!
（渕）ダ… ダメです！
そんな所 行けません！
I-I can't!
I can't go to a place like that!
I'm turning back!
引き返します！
（信）なんでだよ？
Wh-Why?!
Mr. Yuan! You were told by the royal palace to help me, weren't you?
渕さん 王宮から 俺の力になれって
言われてきてるんだろう？
それは そうですが…
そこだけはムリ！ 絶対ムリです！
That's true, but this is too much!
Way too much!
Oh, come on!
いいじゃねえか 暇そうなんだしよ
（渕）そういう問題じゃないんです
You're not doing anything else, are ya?
That's not the problem!
そ… そこは
近づいてはいけない場所なんですよ
Th-That is a place we're not allowed to approach!
許可なく近づけば 殺されても
誰も文句が言えない所…
It's a place where if you get close without permission, no one will object to you being killed.
ウワサでは もう何人も行方不明に
There are rumors that several people that did go went missing!
ウワサだよ ウワサ
Those're just rumors!
The nig-lipped giant...
“唇巨人”… いや “唇将軍”かな
あの人 そんな悪い人じゃないから
Er, big-lipped general...
That guy, he's not actually such a bad guy.
Big-lipped general!?
唇将軍～？
Lord Xin!
信どの
あなた なんて恐ろしいことを…
How could you say such a terrifying thing?!
Here. I'll give ya this. So c'mon.
ほ～ら！ これやるから 頼むよ
What's this?
何ですか？ これは
（信）金！
Money.
No matter how much money you have, it won't be enough.
そんな…
いくら お金をもらってもダメです
I have two lovely children.
私には 玉のような子供が
２人もいる　命が惜しい
My life is dear to me.
Is it, now?
そうか？
アイア～ッ！
ハァ…
（信）フフッ…
Hey, how about we turn back after all?
（渕）やっぱり
行くの やめません？
（信）ダメだ
No!
You sure?
どうしても？
（信）どうしてもだ
Totally sure.
That's the only way I'm gonna get a lot stronger.
俺が もっともっと強くなるには
それっきゃ道がねえ
そうなんですか？
Is that so?
Yeah.
（信）ああ　あのおっさんは
天下の大将軍みてえだからな
That old man looks to be the greatest general under the heavens.
B-But...
（渕）し… しかしですね…
俺は 百人将に任命されたあと
王宮で将軍のことを聞いてみたんだ
After I got appointed as a Hundred-Man General,
I heard more about the general at the royal palace.
（政(せい)）なぜ そんなに
王騎将軍のことが気になるんだ？
Why are you so interested in General Wang Qi?
After talking to him directly on the battlefield, I understood.
戦場で 直接 話をしてみて
分かったんだ
That guy is different from other generals.
あの人は ほかの将軍とは違う
I mean, he's unbelievably huge.
何ていうか… とてつもなく でけえ
圧倒されちまうんだ
It felt overwhelming being near him.
その訳が知りてえんだよ
I want to know the reason for that.
King of Qin Ying Zheng
I see.
（政）なるほど
（政）信…
お前が そう思うのもムリはない
Xin. I don't blame you for thinking that.
確かに
王騎将軍は ただの将軍ではない
It's true. General Wang Qi is no ordinary general.
He is the last remnant of the Six Great Generals of the State of Qin.
秦国六大将軍
その最後の生き残りだ
The Six Great Generals of the State of Qin?
秦国六大将軍？
（政）俺の曽祖父
“戦神(いくさがみ)”といわれた昭王(しょうおう)の時代
In the age of my great grandfather, King Zhao, who was called the God of War,
秦国は間違いなく
中華で最も恐れられた国だった
the State of Qin was without a doubt the most feared state in China.
秦国の軍が
ひと度 行軍を始めれば―
When the State of Qin started marching,
敵は全ての門を固く閉ざしたという
all enemies would shut their gates tight.
Why do you think that is?
なぜだと思う？
The Six Great Generals?
六大将軍か
そうだ　昭王によって
任命された６人の大将軍が―
That's right.
Because the Six Great Generals appointed by King Zhao
中華全土を
所狭しと暴れ回ったからだ
rampaged across all of China.
（政）当時の秦国は―
In those days, the State of Qin was always invading other states and often fought multiple states at once.
常に 他国に侵攻し
数国と同時に戦っていた
The battlefield was far from Xianyang.
戦場は咸陽(かんよう)から遠い
だから 昭王は…
Because of that, King Zhao gave the generals...
Six Great Generals Bai Qi
白起(はくき)…
Bai Qi,
Six Great Generals Wang He
Wang He,
王齕(おうこつ)…
Six Great Generals Hu Shang
胡傷(こしょう)…
Hu Shang,
Six Great Generals Sima Cuo
司馬錯(しばさく)…
Sima Cuo,
Six Great Generals Liao
摎(きょう)…
Liao,
Six Great Generals Wang Qi
and Wang Qi...
そして 王騎
６人の将軍に ある権限を与えた
a certain power.
それは“戦争の自由”
That was freedom of war.
刻一刻と変化する情勢 戦況に対し
Against the state of war, changing moment by moment,
the six generals were allowed to develop these wars on their own discretion.
６人の将軍は 独断で
戦いを展開することを許された
For the other states, it was like there were six dragons rampaging on their own wills
（政）他国からすれば―
独自の意思で暴れ回る６匹の竜が
野に放たれたような心地だったろう
unleashed into the wild...
A-Awesome...
す… すげえ
Yes.
（政）ああ　昭王と六大将軍は―
King Zhao and the Six Great Generals
were linked by strong bonds of loyalty.
揺るぎない鉄の忠誠心で
つながっていた
だから 昭王は“六大将軍”という
制度を作れたんだ
That is why King Zhao created the system of the Six Great Generals.
だが 今や それは伝説に等しい
But now that is nothing more than a legend.
ハハハハッ…
（政）何が おかしいんだ？ 信
What's so funny, Xin?
Because it's so freakin' cool, ain't it, Zheng?
だって メチャクチャ
かっけえじゃねえか 政
That settles it!
（信）これで決まったぜ！
Wait for me, General Wang Qi!
（信）待ってろよ 王騎将軍！
アイアッ！ 信どの 起きて！
（信）ウワッ！
Lord Xin! Wake up!
みみみ… 見えてきました
（信）えっ？
I-I-I can see it!
あ… あれが…
（渕）はい あれが…
That's...
Yes. That's...
General Wang Qi's castle!
（渕）王騎将軍の城です
（王騎）ンッフゥ～…
（信）この中が 王騎将軍の城…
So this is the entrance to General Wang Qi's castle?
開門！ 開門！
（門をたたく音）
Open the gate!
Open the dang gate!
お… およしください 信どの！
殺されてしまいます！
Please stop, Lord Xin!
Open up! Open the gate!
You'll be killed!
What're you so afraid of, Mr. Yuan?
なにビビってんだ？ 渕さん
大丈夫だって
I told you, it'll be fine.
開門！ 開門！
（門をたたく音）
Open the gate!
開いた
It opened.
し… 閉まった
It-It closed...
Hold on a minute, dammit!
…て ちょっと 待て こら！
なんだ そりゃ！
What the hell was that?!
It's me, Xin! We met on the Wei Vice General's hill!
俺は 魏軍(ぎぐん)副将の丘で会った信だ！
（信）おい 副官！ 開けろ！
Hey, aide! Open this thing!
や… やはり
いきなり来てもムリなんですよ
It-It seems that there was no point in coming.
Open it! Open the gate!
一度 戻って 何か方法を…
Perhaps we should go back for now and try to think of some other...
Open it, you bastard!
Oh?
（王騎）おや？
（王騎）これは これは
童 信ではありませんか
What do we have here?
If it isn't Youngster Xin?
Wang Qi
こんな所で
何をしているのですか？
What are you doing in a place like this?
（騰(とう)）
おかえりなさいませ 殿
Welcome back, Lord.
Teng
*Wang Qi's Aide
How did the maneuvers go?
こたびの演習
いかがでした？
ンフフッ… まあまあです
（渕）え… 演習？
They were fine.
M... Maneuvers?
（渕）い… 一体 どんな演習を…
W-What in the world kind of maneuvers were they...
Well for now, I'm glad I met up with him.
（信）とりあえず 会えて良かった
行き当たりばったりで
来ちまったから…
I ended up coming at exactly the right time...
し… しかし この息苦しさは何だ？
B-But what's with this suffocating feeling...?
Even though we met before,
１度 会ってるはずなのに
今も 見てるだけで圧倒されちまう
I'm feeling pressure just from looking at him right now.
これが かつて 天下を
恐れさせた六大将軍のすごさか
So this is the might of someone who was once feared from everywhere under the heavens. One of the Six Great Generals?!
And this is a general's castle!
そして ここが将軍の城
ヘヘッ… 見てっか？ 漂(ひょう)
See that, Piao?!
俺たちが目指す天下の大将軍は―
Both the body and castle of the greatest general under the heavens that we seek to be are gigantic!
人も城も やっぱり でっけえぞ！
（信）え… えっと…
（渕）どうして こんな展開に…
Um...
Wh-Why is this happening...?
それで 私に何か用ですか？
So then,
what business do you have with me?
We'll be starting act two of our maneuvers soon,
すぐに 演習 第２幕を始めるので
手短にお願いしますよ
so I ask you keep it brief.
I came to request that you teach me how to become stronger.
どうしたら もっと強くなれるのか
教えを請いに来ました
フフッ… そうですか
Is that so?
I was certain it had to do with my mhmhm...
私は てっきり
私と“ムフフ”な関係に…
“ムフフ”な関係？
（王騎）オホホッ… 冗談ですよ
Your mhmhm?
Just a joke.
Right, Teng?
ねっ？ 騰
（騰）はっ！
Yes, sir.
（王騎）“教えを請いたい”とは
殊勝な心がけですね
You have quite a commendable attitude to come request teachings.
Perhaps Youngster Xin has grown a little.
童 信も
少しは成長しているようです
But I must say that to suddenly come to me is imprudent.
しかし いきなり私の所に来るとは
やはり思慮が足りませんねえ
I have no reason to look after you, you see.
私に あなたの面倒を見る筋合いは
ありませんからねえ
We have only met once, haven't we?
あなたとは
１度しか会ったことがないのですよ
Would it not be more logical to have Changwenjun oversee you?
むしろ 昌文君(しょうぶんくん)に見てもらうのが
筋ではありませんか？
（信）昌文君じゃダメだ
Changwenjun isn't good enough.
俺は 天下の大将軍に
修行をつけてほしいんだ
I want to be trained by the greatest general under the heavens!
（信）確かに
将軍が俺の相手をする筋合いはない
It's true that I don't have any reason for you to take me on.
But there is a benefit for you!
だけど 利はある！
Oh? What exactly?
（王騎）
ほう… どんなことですか？
I'll become strong enough to be your right hand in no time!
（信）
俺は あっという間に あんたの
右腕くらいにはなってみせる
And the more strong generals there are, the larger the wars will become.
強(つえ)え将が多けりゃ―
更に でっかい戦を
描けるようになるからな
それが利だ！
（渕）し… 信どの
That's your benefit!
L-Lord Xin!
There aren't words to describe how too far you're going!
言うに事欠いて
それは あまりに大きく出過ぎです
（渕）こ… 殺されますよ…
W-We'll be killed...
確かに おバカは
一度 死なねば 直らないようですね
It's true that if a fool does not die once, he will never heal.
（渕）マ… マズイ…
O-Oh no...
いいでしょう　それでは 童 信も
湯から上がって準備しなさい
All right then, Youngster Xin.
Get out of the bath and get prepared.
So you mean you'll take me on your maneuvers?!
…てことは 俺も演習に？
（王騎）フフフッ… 違いますよ
（信）えっ？
No.
I'll be bringing you to an even more fun place, Youngster Xin.
童 信は もっと楽しい所に
連れていってあげます
（渕）い… 一体
どこに連れていかれるのでしょう
Wh-Where in the world do you think we're being taken?
しかも なんで私まで巻き添えに…
私には 玉のような２人の子供が…
And why am I now getting involved?
I have two precious children...
いいかげん覚悟決めろって 渕さん
（渕）ハァ…
C'mon already and work up some resolve.
If there's anything you'd like to ask, feel free to ask.
何か聞きたいことがあったら
質問してもいいですよ
前にも言いましたが―
I mentioned it before, but you won't get many chances to talk to me like this.
この私との会話の機会は
そうありませんからねえ
Then could you tell me about the legendary Six Great Generals?
じゃ 伝説の六大将軍のことを
教えてください
You're quite learned to know about something so old.
よく そんな古いものを
知ってましたね
I'm quite surprised to hear those words come out of your mouth, Youngster Xin.
童 信の口から
その言葉が出るとは 驚きです
I heard about it from Zheng at the royal palace.
（信）王宮で 政から聞いたんだ
He said the Six Great Generals were a system created by King Zhao...
“六大将軍は
昭王が作った制度だ”って
“制度”…
System?
どうも あなた方は 六大将軍を
少々 誤解しているようですね
It would seem that you have some slight misapprehensions regarding the Six Great Generals.
Misapprehensions?
誤解？
（王騎）私たち六大将軍は―
We Six Great Generals ran through many a battlefield.
あまたの戦場を駆け抜け
あまたの敵を葬ってきました
And buried many foes.
( Flag - Wang )
And the result
その結果…
was by simply approaching caused enemies bow down to us
近寄るだけで 敵は平伏し
城を明け渡すほどに―
and surrender their castles.
その６人の武名は
中華全土に響き渡りました
The military renown of those six resounded throughout all of China.
武名が中華全土に…
Your military renown was...
across all of China...?!
（王騎）そこで 昭王は
我々が更に動きやすいようにと―
And then in order for us to move even more easily,
King Zhao created the Six General System.
六将制度を作ったのです
つまり 制度の前に
ケタ外れに強い我々６人がいた
In other words, even before the system was established, we six were extraordinarily strong.
You have things backwards.
話は逆です　ねっ？ 騰
（騰）はっ！
Isn't that right, Teng?
Yes, sir!
実のないところに制度を作っても
意味がありません
There would be no point to making the system from insubstantial resources.
（王騎）童 信…
あなたは六大将軍のことを―
Youngster Xin, you called the Six Great Generals "legends", did you not?
“伝説”と言いましたよね？
（信）えっ？ はい
Uh, yeah.
（王騎）なぜ私たちが伝説なのか
Are you aware of the reason for which we are legends?
その訳をご存じですか？
（信）い… いえ
N-No.
そうでしょうねえ
では 教えてあげましょう ンフッ…
I expected not.
Then allow me to impart it to you.
（王騎）確かに 今の秦国にも
“将軍”と名の付く人間はいます
It is true that even in the current State of Qin,
there are humans with the title of general.
しかし 残念ながら―
But unfortunately,
もはや“六大将軍”の名に
見合うだけの人間が１人もいない
there is not a single person who could measure up to the title of the Six Great Generals.
つまり 私たちの後を継ぐだけの
将がいなかったということですよ
Meaning that no generals truly succeeded us.
しかし 六大将軍の強さは
時を経ても 人々の記憶に残った
But even as time has passed,
the strength of the Six Great Generals has not been forgotten.
だから 私たちは伝説なのです
That is why we are legends.
す… すげえ
やっぱり この人は 天下の大将軍だ
A-Awesome.
I knew this guy was
the greatest general under the heavens!
So then, you want to become a general, Youngster Xin?
それで？
童 信は将軍になりたいのですか？
天下の大将軍に！
（王騎）ほう…
The greatest general under the heavens!
So you wish to rise up to my level?
この私のところまで
上ってきたいと…
Do you hear me, Xin?
（漂）いいな？ 信
Piao
*Now deceased, Xin's childhood friend
（漂）俺たちは
天下の大将軍になって
We're going to become the greatest generals under the heavens,
and etch our names into history!
歴史に名を刻むんだ
天下の大将軍…
Greatest generals under the heavens...?
（信）いや 違う
（王騎）うん？
No, not that.
俺は あんたを超える
I'll surpass you!
I will become the strongest Great General under the heavens and etch my name into history!
俺は 天下で最強の大将軍になって
歴史に名を刻むんだ！
アイア～ッ！
“天下最強”と来ましたか
ココココッ…
Strongest under the heavens, is it?
どうですか？ 騰
（騰）はっ！ 度肝(どぎも)を抜かれました
What do you think of that, Teng?
Yes. I'm quite taken aback.
Even for a fool, to come through to where you are you must have quite some talent, Youngster Xin.
おバカも そこまで突き抜けると
立派な才能ですよ 童 信
いいでしょう　気に入りましたよ
All right. You've piqued my interest.
しかし その実現のためには
相当な努力が必要ですよ
But realizing that goal would require quite a bit of effort.
死をもいとわぬ努力がね
Indeed, so much effort that it may kill you.
分かってる
だから 将軍のもとに来たんだ
I know.
That's why I came to find a general.
ほう… その覚悟はできていると？
（信）当たり前だ
Oh? So you say you have that resolve?
Of course!
I don't care how rigorous it is!
どんなに過酷でもかまわねえ
絶対 やり遂げてみせる！
I'm definitely gonna do it!
So please, train me, General Wang Qi!
だから
俺に修行をつけてくれ 王騎将軍！
I don't want to.
イヤです
アアーッ！
（渕）信どの！
Lord Xin!
アッ アッ… ウワッ！
（池に落ちる音）
（渕）ハァ…
ハァ… 何しやがる！
（渕）お… 王騎将軍
What the fuck are you doing?!
G-General Wang Qi!
ど… どういうおつもりですか？
あんまりです
Wh-What were you intending?!
This is too much!
“どういうおつもり”って
修行ですよ 修行
What was I intending? That was training.
はぁ…
これのどこが修行だというのです？
Wh-What about this was training?
何を言っているのですか？ あなた
What are you talking about?
The training has now started.
（王騎）
修行は 今から始まるのですよ
A-A battlefield?
（信）せ… 戦場
（王騎）ここは
秦国内に いくつか点在する―
This is one of the many stateless regions located inside the borders of the State of Qin.
無国籍地帯のひとつです
（渕）無国籍地帯…
Stateless regions?
（王騎）作物も育たず
秦国も見捨てた この荒れ野に―
This wasteland is not used for agriculture and has even been discarded by the State of Qin.
Fighting for the land, a few parties from tribes and ruined states have flowed into it.
戦で土地を追われた少数部族や
亡国の輩(やから)が流れ込んできた
そして また その中で戦っている
この狭い荒野の覇を争って
And they now fight inside it.
A war for dominance over this small wasteland.
They're all incorrigible fools.
救いようのないバカ者たちです
（王騎）童 信
（信）ハッ…
Youngster Xin!
Please subjugate this land.
この地を平定してみせなさい
（信）平定…
Subjugate?
（渕）ムチャですよ　平定って…
たった１人で何ができるんです？
Th-That's absurd!
Subjugate it?
What can one person do?!
I'm not particularly expectant about the military force of one person.
別に
１人の武など期待していませんよ
何のために
剣を預かったと思っているんです？
Why do you think I took custody of your sword?
H-Huh?
あっ あれ？
（王騎）童 信！
あなたが落ちた集落の南芭(なんは)族は―
Youngster Xin.
The settlement you fell into belongs to the Nanba Tribe.
Which among the 10 tribes here, are the weakest.
この地にいる10の諸族の中で最弱
I do believe I've heard they have a population of 100.
人口は
100人といったところでしょうか
100人？
100?!
百人将になる前に
こいつらを率いて戦えってのか？
So he's saying that before I become a Hundred-Man General, I have to lead these guys in a fight?
それが 王騎流の修行か！
So that's the Wang Qi style of training?!
（南芭族たち）破られたぞ！
（老人）く… 来るぞ！
They broke through!
H-Here they come!
あの防衛線… 老人と女？
Is that defensive line made up of women and the elderly?
Protect it even if it costs you your life!
（老人Ａ）命に代えても守り抜け！
ここは我らの土地！
This is our land!
（敵兵たち）オリャー！
王騎将軍！
（王騎）フフッ…
General Wang Qi!
Mom! Mom! Mom!
（公(こう)）おっ母！ おっ母！ おっ母！
（母親）公！
Gong!
ハッ… ダメ！ イヤーッ！
（公）おっ母！ おっ母！
No, stop!
Mom! Mom!
（蹴る音）
（信）バカ野郎！
You moron!
（敵兵）うん？ なんだ てめえは！
Who the hell are you?
You old guys form five-man teams and attack individual enemies!
じいさんらは
５人１組になって 敵１人をやれ！
The women should retreat and back them up with long spears!
女は
下がった所から 長槍(ながやり)で援護だ！
そこのあなた
童 信に伝えておきなさい
You, there.
Please tell this to Youngster Xin.
I will train him after he's subjugated the land.
“平定が終わったら
私が修行をつけてやる”と
ええっ？ 私も下に？
（王騎）おイヤですか？
Huh?! You want me down there, too?
Are you refusing?
なんでしたら あなたも 童 信同様
私が蹴り落としてあげますが
In that case, I will need to kick you down there just like Youngster Xin.
N-No need.
い… いえ… 自分で下ります
I will go down on my own.
（王騎）もっとも
あの程度の敵で苦戦するようでは
Although, if that level of enemy results in a close fight,
there won't be training or anything of the sort.
修行も何もありませんけどねえ
フフフフッ…
わ… 分かりました　伝えます
I-I understand.
I'll tell him.
（老人）ウワッ！
（信）うん？
Don't panic!
焦るな！
５人で１人を取り囲めばいいんだ！
It'll be fine if you surround one person with a group of five!
O-Okay!
（老人Ｂ）は… はい
ここは俺が防ぐ！
その隙に柵を直すんだ！
I'll hold off this area!
Use this chance to fix the fence!
（敵兵）一斉にかかれ！
（騒ぎ声）
Everyone, attack at once!
Come get me,
かかってきやがれ 雑魚どもが！
small fries!
アイア～ッ！
These guys are all elderly people, women, and children, ain't they?!
こいつら みんな
年寄りと女と子供じゃねえか
俺はな 自分より弱いヤツを
いたぶるヤツは大嫌(でえきれ)えなんだ！
I fuckin' hate people who torment people weaker than them!
Get ready!
（信）覚悟しろ！
（敵兵）こ… こいつ バケモノだ！
Th-This guy's a monster!
（敵兵たち）ウワーッ！
（渕）
皆さん！ 何をしているんです？
What are you doing, everyone?!
Now is your best chance to counterattack!
今が反撃の好機です！
（老人）あの… あなたは？
Um, who are you?
私は渕！ あの信どのの… あ～…
I am Yuan.
I'm that boy, Lord Xin's...
Yes! His aide!
そう！ 副官です！
（老人たち）副官どの？
Aide?
はい… こまごまと
説明している暇はありません
I don't have time to explain in detail.
さあ 私に続いてください
（老人Ｂ）へ… へい
Come, follow after me!
（老人Ｂ）皆の衆 いくぞい！
（老人たち）オーッ！
Everyone, let's go!
うん？ お前ら… 渕さんも！
You guys...
And Mr. Yuan?!
Good! Follow me!
いいぞ！ 俺に続け！
What're you bastards doing attacking elderly and women?!
（暁定(ぎょうてい)）てめえら！ 年寄りと
女相手に なに てこずってんだ！
B-Boss...
（敵兵）お… お頭…
This monstrous kid showed up!
バケモンみてえな小僧が現れて…
（暁定）でえ？
フッ… おっさんが親玉らしいな
Looks like you're the top dog, old man.
You got beaten by this kid?!
こんな小僧にやられただ？
バカ野郎が！
You damn morons!
デエ～ッ！
You guys are so noisy!
てめえら やかましいんだよ！
静かにしやがれ！
Quiet the hell down!
気をつけてくだされ
Do be careful.
That man is called Xiao Ding.
あの男は暁定といって
ここいらいちばんの暴れ者ですじゃ
He's the most violent ruffian among them.
いちばんの暴れ者？ 声が
でけえだけのバカじゃねえのか？
Most violent ruffian, huh?
Ain't he just a loud idiot?
What did you just say, kid?!
小僧！ 今 何か言ったな？
（信）耳だけは いいみたいだな
Looks like his ears work well enough, though.
ほざくのも今のうちだ
Talk while you can!
デエ～ッ！ デエッ！
野郎… 口先だけじゃねえ
Bastard!
He's not all talk!
And I can't do shit with just this spear.
しかも
こんな槍じゃ どうしようもねえな
よし！
Okay!
トリャー！
こんなもんで勝ったと思ったか？
Did you think that was enough to win?!
（信）しまった… 浅かったか
Dammit! It was shallow!
死ね 小僧！
Die, kid!
き… 貴様ら… アアッ！
Y-You bastards!
い… 今だ！ 突け！
（老人たち）ウオーッ！
Now! Charge!
（暁定）バ… バカな！
This can't be!
Now!
（老人たち）今じゃ！
（女性たち）ヤーッ！
（敵兵たち）ウワーッ！
信どの！
（信）ああ
Lord Xin!
Yeah.
敵は逃げ出した！
この機を逃(のが)すな！
The enemy is retreating!
Don't miss this chance!
Everyone, follow my lead!
みんな 俺に続け！
敵を蹴散らすぞ！
Let's rout the enemy!
（王騎）
ココココッ… 初戦とはいえ
敵が弱すぎましたかねえ？ 騰
Though this is his first battle,
the enemy may have been too weak, eh, Teng?
Yes, sir.
はっ！ 手応えがなさすぎます
They seem to have been too little of a resistance.
フフフッ… まあ これからです
Well, it's only just beginning.
童 信… まずは そこで学びなさい
率いることの難しさと―
Youngster Xin, from there, you must first learn
both the difficulty of leading and the strength of fighting in groups.
集団で戦うことの強さを
王騎将軍 待ってろよ
General Wang Qi, wait for me!
No matter what it takes, I'll subjugate this land!
俺は必ず この地を平定してやる！
michi wa tsuzuku yume wo oimotome
路は続く　夢を追い求め
The path goes on, chasing after a dream.
nozomu saki ni kimi no ashita wa aru no?
望む先に　君の明日はあるの？
Will your tomorrow be at the place my hopes lead?
kizutsuite kokoro mo mada kawaku nara
傷ついて　心もまだ渇くなら
If I get hurt and my heart is still thirsty,
koko e kite nando demo utau kara
ここへ来て何度でも歌うから
I'll come here and sing as many times as it takes.
owari naki tatakai no naka de
終わりなき戦いの中で
In this endless battle
kimi wa tsuyoku kawaru
君は強く変わる
You change to become stronger.
kono sora wo kirisaita ikazuchi wa kimi
この空を切り裂いた　雷は君
The lightning that cut apart this sky is you.
osore wo koete tachimukau hikari no ya hashiridasu
恐れを超えて立ち向かう　光の矢　走りだす
The arrow of light that overcomes fear faces forward and shoots forth.
tsukamu sadame shinjitsuzukeru no...
掴む　運命　信じ続けるの…
I'll grab onto the destiny I've always believed in...
～♪
Preview
（昌文君）
１人だけいる　攻めと守りの
強さを兼ね備えた最強の武将が
Alone is fine.
With the combined strength of his attack and defense,
he is the ultimate military commander!
The greatest crisis in the State of Qin!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）秦国最大の危機
沈黙を破り
眠れる“怪鳥”が動きだす
Breaking through the silence, a sleeping captain starts to move!
Appointment
End
次回 “任命”
Next time,